Blinkist User Research Privacy Policy
=====================================

**Last Edited: October, 2021**

First of all, we (“**Blinkist**”) would like to thank you for participating in our user research. This is incredibly helpful for us to be able to constantly improve our product. We want you to feel confident that your data is in safe hands when you participate in our user research, which is why we’re committing to collect, use and process your personal data only in accordance with this Blinkist User Research Privacy Policy and with all relevant legal data protection regulations. By participating in our user research, you agree that we may process your personal data as described herein.

Below we give you more information about our data protection regulations. Please note that not all of these regulations apply to you in each and every case - this means, we do not use every single tool in every single case. In particular, if we conduct an online interview with you and we want to record it, we will of course always explicitly inform you of this.

### RESPONSIBLE ENTITY & CONTACT DETAILS

The entity responsible for processing your personal data in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is Blinks Labs GmbH, Sonnenallee 223, 12059 Berlin, Germany (“**Blinkist**”). You can contact our privacy team at any time for further information on privacy issues via email at [\[email protected\]](https://www.blinkist.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). Our data protection officer is Benjamin Kühn, and he can be reached either by post \[HC Plus | Geneststraße 5 | D-10829 Berlin\] or via the above mentioned email address, under the subject “For the attention of the data protection officer”.

### COLLECTING, PROCESSING, AND USING YOUR PERSONAL DATA

#### PERSONAL DATA

Personal data means any information which is related to an identified or identifiable natural person. This includes (for example), but is not limited to, your name, email address, or photo or video material of your person that is created during the User Research. This may also include your age range, gender identity, country of residence or comfort with the English language - as this data is not necessarily personal in itself, but a combination of all this data can be used to identify you as a person.

#### COLLECTING, PROCESSING, AND USING PERSONAL DATA

For the purposes of managing Blinkist’s User Research, we will collect, process, and use your personal data that you have disclosed to us, that means if you have expressly consented pursuant to Art. 6 (1) (a) GDPR - usually this means that you have submitted a consent form with your data or, for example, an application for the Blinkist User Research Panel. With the exception of any mandatory fields marked with asterisks, you decide yourself which data you are willing to enter and share with us.

Your data will be transmitted to the user research department in charge and used exclusively for the purposes of the respective research study. This also includes using the data to contact you. Your data will not be disclosed to any third party – other than in the context of data processing commissions – without your express consent.

#### COLLECTION OF YOUR DATA: TYPEFORM AND GOOGLE FORMS

To initially collect your data, we primarily use two tools: Typeform (Typeform, S.L., Carrer Bac de Roda, 163, 08018 Barcelona, Spain) and Google Forms (Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland, “Google”; Parent company: Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, California 94043 USA). The data processing takes place on the basis of our legitimate interests (Art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR) for the technically error-free and optimized provision of our services. Typeform receives secure user IDs for this purpose.

For more information about Typeform’s data processing, please refer to the [Typeform Privacy Policy](https://admin.typeform.com/to/dwk6gt/?typeform-source=www.google.com). For more information about Google’s data processing, please refer to the [Google Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en). We have entered into a so-called “Data Processing Agreement” with both companies, in which we commit them to protect the data of our customers, to not disclose them to third parties and to comply with the provisions of the standard contractual clauses according to Art. 46 GDPR in the case of a transfer of personal data via sub-processors or affiliates to the USA or other countries that do not have a level of data protection that complies with the GDPR.

#### SCHEDULING INTERVIEW SESSIONS: CALENDLY

To schedule our interview sessions with you as a User Research participant, we use Calendly LLC (“Calendly”, 271 17th St NW, Atlanta, GA 30363, USA). For more information about data protection related to Calendly, please see the [Calendly Privacy Policy](https://calendly.com/privacy). We have entered into a so-called “Data Processing Agreement” with Calendly, in which we commit them to protect the data of our customers, to not disclose them to third parties and to comply with the provisions of the standard contractual clauses according to Art. 46 GDPR in the case of a transfer of personal data via sub-processors or affiliates to the USA or other countries that do not have a level of data protection that complies with the GDPR.

### STORING OF YOUR DATA

#### GOOGLE DRIVE AND GOOGLE SHEETS

We use two more of Google’s products to store, sort and filter your data to subsequently review and contact user research participants: Google Drive and a Google Sheets integration with Typeform. Access to this Google Sheet on Google Drive is limited to the User Research department in charge and is used exclusively for the purposes of the research study recruitment process.

#### CONFLUENCE

We use Confluence as an internal collaboration space where we might store your data to subsequently view it. Access to Confluence is limited to Blinkist employees only.

Provider of Confluence is Atlassian Pty Ltd (“Atlassian”), Level 6, 341 George Street, Sydney NSW 2000, Australia. For more information about data protection related to Atlassian, please see the [Atlassian Privacy Policy](https://www.atlassian.com/legal/privacy-policy). We have entered into a so-called “Data Processing Agreement” with Atlassian in which we commit Atlassian to protect the data of our customers, to not disclose them to third parties and to comply with the provisions of the standard contractual clauses (SCC) according to Art. 46 GDPR in the case of a transfer of personal data to the USA or other countries that do not have a level of data protection that complies with the GDPR.

#### DOVETAIL

We use Dovetail as an internal space where we might store your data (including videos and photographs) to subsequently view it and integrate it in other tools, such as Zoom.

Provider of Dovetail is Dovetail Research Pty. Ltd (“Dovetail”), Level 1/276 Devonshire St, Surry Hills NSW 2010, Australia. For more information about data protection related to Dovetail, please see the [Dovetail Privacy Policy](https://dovetailapp.com/help/user-privacy-policy/). We have entered into a so-called “Data Processing Agreement” with Dovetail in which we commit Dovetail to protect the data of our customers, to not disclose them to third parties and to comply with the provisions of the standard contractual clauses according to Art. 46 GDPR in the case of a transfer of personal data to the USA, Australia, or other countries that do not have a level of data protection that complies with the GDPR.

#### GREATQUESTION

We use GreatQuestion as an internal space where we might store your data (including videos and photographs) to subsequently view it and integrate it in other tools, such as Zoom.

Provider of GreatQuestion is Great Question, Inc. (“GreatQuestion”), 418 45th Street, Oakland, CA USA. For more information about data protection related to GreatQuestion, please see the [GreatQuestion Privacy Policy](https://greatquestion.co/privacy). We have entered into a so-called “Data Processing Agreement” with GreatQuestion in which we commit GreatQuestion to protect the data of our customers, to not disclose them to third parties and to comply with the provisions of the standard contractual clauses according to Art. 46 GDPR in the case of a transfer of personal data to the USA.

### UNMODERATED REMOTE TESTING VIA USERTESTING AND MY RECRUIT

Occasionally we will send invites to participate in a remote unmoderated user test that is hosted and launched via the UserTesting platform and a URL generated by their My Recruit service. We use UserTesting to be able to launch unmoderated app, website and prototype test sessions concerning Blinkist or other related products. Participation in these tests are of course voluntary.

By participating in the study, your voice and screen will be recorded only during the session. UserTesting ceases collecting any information after the session ends and does not record your mouse clicks or keystrokes. UserTesting does not access your files or monitor anything from your device. Following the completion of the session, a recording is made available to the Blinkist User Research department. We may then highlight certain parts of the feedback that you provided, and share your feedback and video with our Design and Product teams to spark discussion, generate and validate product ideas and solutions. Videos are stored in an encrypted form on UserTesting and can’t be viewed by the public.

Provider of the UserTesting Platform and My Recruit is USER TESTING, INC., 660 4th Street #246, San Francisco, CA 94107, United States of America (“UserTesting”). For more information about data protection related to UserTesting, please see the [UserTesting Privacy Policy](https://www.usertesting.com/privacy-policy). For more information about how the information is being used and your privacy related to My Recruit, please see the [My Recruit Privacy Guide](https://help.usertesting.com/hc/en-us/articles/360039059892-My-Recruit-Privacy-Guide#h_bdffecb2-aafe-488d-88de-161d9abbd5b2). We have entered into a so-called “Data Processing Agreement” with UserTesting, in which we commit UserTesting to protect the data of our customers, to not disclose them to third parties and to comply with the provisions of the standard contractual clauses according to Art. 46 GDPR in the case of a transfer of personal data to the USA.

### SESSION RECORDINGS WITH USABILITYHUB AND LOOKBACK

From time to time and and only following your prior consent, we record user testing/research sessions via UsabilityHub, a screen recording service provided by UsabilityHub Pty Ltd, 290-292 Wellington Street, Collingwood, VIC 3066, Australia (“UsabilityHub”) and Lookback, a screen recording service provided by Lookback Group, Inc, 470 Ramona St, Palo Alto CA 94301, USA (“Lookback”). By participating in the Screen recording session, your face, voice and screen might be recorded during the session.

We have entered into so-called “Data Processing Agreements” with UsabilityHub and Lookback, in which we commit both companies to protect the data of our customers, to not disclose them to third parties and to comply with the provisions of the standard contractual clauses according to Art. 46 GDPR in the case of a transfer of personal data to the USA or other countries that do not have a level of data protection that complies with the GDPR.

### VIDEO RECORDINGS WITH ZOOM

From time to time and only following your prior consent, we record user testing/research sessions via Zoom, a video conferencing service provided by Zoom Video Communications, Inc., 55 Almaden Blvd. Suite 600, San Jose, CA 95113, USA (“Zoom”). By participating in the Zoom session, your face, voice and screen might be recorded during the session.

We have entered into a so-called “Data Processing Agreement” with Zoom, in which we commit Zoom to protect the data of our customers, to not disclose them to third parties and to comply with the provisions of the standard contractual clauses according to Art. 46 GDPR in the case of a transfer of personal data to the USA or other countries that do not have a level of data protection that complies with the GDPR.

### PROVISION OF INCENTIVES

To show our appreciation for your participation in our user research, we may provide you with incentives. For this, we use Tremendous (GiftRocket Inc, 228 Park Ave S #62949, New York, New York 10003, USA, “Tremendous”). For more information about data protection related to Tremendous, please see the [Tremendous Privacy Policy](https://www.tremendous.com/privacy). In order to be able to provide you with the incentive, we need to submit your email address to Tremendous. This data transfer is accordingly based on your consent if you wish to receive the incentive offered to you, Art. 7 GDPR. Please note that data transfer to the USA involves risks, as the same data protection standards may not apply there as they do in Germany/the EU.

### YOU HAVE THE FOLLOWING RIGHTS

* Pursuant to Article 7(3) GDPR, you have the right to revoke at any time any consent declaration you may have given to us before. Consequently, we may no longer continue the respective activity.
    
* Pursuant to Article 15 GDPR, you have the right to demand information on your personal data which we have processed. In particular, you have the right to information on the following:
    
    * Purposes of the data processing
        
    * The category of personal data
        
    * The categories of recipients to which we disclosed or will disclose your data
        
    * The planned storage periods of data
        
    * The existence of the right to correction, deletion, restriction of processing and objection
        
    * The right to appeal
        
    * The right to know the origin of your data in the event that we did not collect these data
        
    * The right to meaningful and detailed information on the existence of automated decision-making including profiling and, if applicable, relevant information on the details thereof
        
* Pursuant to Article 16 GDPR, you have the right to the immediate correction of incorrect personal data and/or the completion of incomplete personal data in our storage.
    
* Pursuant to Article 17 GDPR, you have the right to the deletion of your personal data unless the deletion interferes with the execution of the right to the free expression of opinions and to information, with the compliance with legal obligations, is necessary in the public interest or for establishing, exercising or defending legal claims.
    
* Pursuant to Article 18 GDPR, you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data if you contest or challenge the accuracy of these data, the processing of the data is illegal, but you reject the deletion of these data and we no longer need the data while you still need the data to establish, exercise or defend legal claims or you have raised an objection against the data processing pursuant to Article 21 GDPR.
    
* Pursuant to Article 20 GDPR, you have the right to receive the personal data you provided to us in a structured, customary and machine-readable format or to demand the transfer to another authority.
    
* Pursuant to Article 77 GDPR, you have the right to complain to a superior authority. As a rule, you may find such authority at your place of residence, your workplace or our company domicile.

### DATA SECURITY

We transmit all your personal data using the widely used and secure TLS (Transport Layer Security) encryption standard. The TLS protocol is a proven and secure standard that is also used in online banking transactions. You will recognise a secure TLS connection by the “s” following the http (https://…) in your browser URL or by the lock symbol in the lower section of your browser.

Moreover, we use suitable technical and organisational safety procedures to protect your data against accidental or wilful manipulation, partial or complete loss, destruction or against the unauthorised access by third parties. We constantly improve these security measures as technology advances.

### CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS

We take the data protection regulations of the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”) and the California Civil Code seriously and respect the resulting rights for California residents as stated in the following paragraphs. We will not discriminate against you for exercising your rights under the CCPA. We will not deny you our goods or services, charge you different prices or rates, or provide you a lower quality of goods and services if you exercise your rights under the CCPA.

### SHINE THE LIGHT / OPT-OUT

California residents have the right to request information about their personal data that we have shared with third parties once a calendar year and to have this data deleted by us. In addition, California residents have the right to opt-out of the disclosure of their personal data to third parties (“opt-out”). To exercise the right to information and / or deletion and/ or opt-out, an informal email to us [\[email protected\]](https://www.blinkist.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) is sufficient, along with proof of identity and place of residence. We will respond to verified requests within 30 days. California residents also have the right to opt-out of the sale of their personal data. We do not offer this option, because we generally do not sell personal data.

### PURPOSES OF DATA PROCESSING OF CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS

We collect and process personal data of California residents only for the purposes stated in this data privacy policy, in particular in order to be able to provide our service and our websites in a technically flawless manner, to analyze user behavior to optimize our offer. We do not sell personal data of California residents, we only pass them on to fulfill our business purposes as stated above and in the data privacy policy.

### CATEGORIES OF PERSONAL DATA OF CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS

We collect and process personal data from California residents, which are made available to us directly or through interactions with our services and websites, from the following categories: (i) personal data (e.g. name), (ii) identifiers (e.g. name, email address), (iii) Information about activities on the Internet or networks. The categories of third parties to whom we may share California residents’ personal information are: (i) analytics and hosting providers. We have no knowledge of disclosing personal data of minors under 16 years of age to third parties.

### Log in to Blinkist

or

### Sign up for Blinkist

Powerful ideas  
—15 minutes at a time
--------------------------------------

###### Editorial

###### Useful Links

###### Company

Powerful ideas  
—15 minutes at a time
--------------------------------------

* © Blinkist 2024
